<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David A Seeman</title>
    <description>Dave Seeman&#39;s blog</description>
    <link>http://daveas.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://daveas.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 11:41:37 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 11:41:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Multitasking with BetterSnapTool</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently started to pick up some web design and web development skills because I want to create my own web applications. I was learning with &lt;a href=&quot;http://mbsy.co/9tG6V&quot;&gt;One Month Rails&lt;/a&gt; and using a program called BetterSnapTool&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to organize my desktop in a way that fit how I wanted to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the preferences section you can create custom keyboard shortcuts to make this a much more useful application. Highlighted in green, I assigned &lt;code&gt;opt&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; to snap the window to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purplemath.com/modules/plane3.htm&quot;&gt;quadrant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;http://postachio-images.s3-website-us-east-1.amazonaws.com/6e4477b91d0f812c91229b0e7499c22c.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-love-an-organized-desktop&quot;&gt;I love an organized desktop!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding those shortcuts made it easy to arrange the windows so I am 1-click away from any window. Sure I could swipe over with full screen apps or use cmd+tab to switch between active apps, but I found this to be by far the most effective workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://postachio-images.s3-website-us-east-1.amazonaws.com/5abc764b4037f6cb3918f85c9730a802.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/bettersnaptool/id417375580?mt=12&quot;&gt;Better Snap Tool&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://daveas.me/posts/Multitasking-with-BetterSnapTool/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daveas.me/posts/Multitasking-with-BetterSnapTool/</guid>
        
        <category>How I Work</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why any Web/Mobile founder should learn to code (Hint - MVP)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a recent grad with a defunct startup, I am looking to join a more stable company. In my job search I came across a very cool company that seemed to be very active in launching new ventures and projects. It just so happens I had met one of their employees in the past so I reached out to her to see if they were hiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, she was gracious enough to forward along my information and we eventually got to talking. Their interview process (which is not quite over) involved coming up with a project for the company so I created a simple one-page website to showcase my project. I also used some design skills I picked up while working on Willow List to make this nifty logo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://postachio-images.s3-website-us-east-1.amazonaws.com/1c303cdec342ea88d68a771630c26be0.png&quot; alt=&quot;text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-value-of-coding&quot;&gt;The Value of Coding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1455520020/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1455520020&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=willis0d-20&amp;amp;linkId=4AUMJC6MB4F3OGYS&quot;&gt;Without Their Permission&lt;/a&gt; by Alexis Ohanian who is a big proponent of the “build first” methodology for startups. By creating a super basic version of your idea and showing it to people, you can get a much bigger reaction than just talking about an idea. The best part is, as Alexis consistently points out, &lt;strong&gt;anyone can do this!&lt;/strong&gt; I put in about 15 hours+ on Codeacademy (so far!) and now I can quickly put together a one-page website to communicate ideas to anyone anywhere in the world. Amazing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here it is, my minimum viable product for the project I created for my interview. It may not look good in every browser or on every device, but remember, I’m new at this! You can find it at &lt;a href=&quot;http://laboratore.godownwind.co&quot;&gt;laboratore.godownwind.co&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Full disclosure:&lt;/em&gt; at the time of this writing I am still speaking with said company, hence I did not disclose their name!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. - I created this page using the “Pages” feature of GitHub. You can find me on GitHub &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/dseeman&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; - and a future post is coming on how to use this GitHub feature to easily create static one-page websites for your next project!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://daveas.me/posts/Why-any-web-mobile-founder-should-learn-to-code-Hint-MVP/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daveas.me/posts/Why-any-web-mobile-founder-should-learn-to-code-Hint-MVP/</guid>
        
        <category>Coding</category>
        
        <category>Startups</category>
        
        <category>Learning</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Exciting Noob Success - Thanks Codeacademy!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Codeacademy and the “inspect element” feature in Safari (Developer tools turned on) I was able to figure out what code I had to add to the source for this theme to center all images and post titles which were both previously left-justified. I just put the code below between immediately after the link to the CSS (so that my formatting will override that of the penso.CSS file).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://postachio-images.s3-website-us-east-1.amazonaws.com/4169272f9bba9eab36e8cbc32bc5ac07.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll see I also made all h3 headings centered which will allow me to page-center subheadings by just adding “###” before the text within my notes. I had wanted this ability before but had not the means to add it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now my blog looks better. So thank you &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codecademy.com&quot;&gt;Codeacademy&lt;/a&gt;, and thank you &lt;a href=&quot;http://postach.io&quot;&gt;Postach.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;update-help-from-postachios-brandon-brown&quot;&gt;Update: Help from Postach.io’s Brandon Brown:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brandon was kind enough to message me with another suggestion for how to center images. He also noted that this code bit belongs in the head of the html file. This is definitely a more proper way to write this, so thank you Brandon for your help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://postachio-images.s3-website-us-east-1.amazonaws.com/92111499dd58a66c6fd3be48dde4221f.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;update-including-pages&quot;&gt;Update: Including Pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will actually want to include both .post-content and .page-content so that your pages have the same justification for photos :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://daveas.me/posts/Exciting-Noob-Success-Thanks-Codeacademy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daveas.me/posts/Exciting-Noob-Success-Thanks-Codeacademy/</guid>
        
        <category>Coding</category>
        
        <category>Learning</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I Learned from Starting a Business in College</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ownership Trumps Investment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cash Trumps Advice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preparation is Paramount&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No Plan Survives First Contact&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait to Spend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Or just don’t&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put it in Writing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Welcome Serendipity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trust your Gut&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It Will Take a LOT of your Time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It Will Take a LOT of your Attention&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be Intentional about your Time and Attention&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Know When to say No&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Know When to call it Quits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Can’t do it Alone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Or even close&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard all of these things before. And yet, we all end up learning them the hard way eventually. But in the end…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://postachio-images.s3-website-us-east-1.amazonaws.com/e854fa10d95117260732b32f829e69df.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://daveas.me/posts/What-I-Learned-from-Starting-a-Business-in-College/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daveas.me/posts/What-I-Learned-from-Starting-a-Business-in-College/</guid>
        
        <category>Startups</category>
        
        <category>Cofounders</category>
        
        <category>Funding</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learn to Code - Codeacademy vs. Treehouse</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My analysis is simple. When you pay for Treehouse, what you’re really paying for is some more hand-holding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both are designed with different tracks you can follow, like learning to build a website or an iPhone app. Both involve entering specific code into an editor to determine if you’re comprehending the lessons. But for anyone with a decent aptitude for coding can do quite well with Codeacademy. The extra videos in Treehouse explain concepts in greater depth, but they also add a lot of time. I started out doing both for about a week and quickly discovered that my lessons were moving about two thirds faster in Codeacademy. So if you are self-driven to learn this new skill but are unsure of your own ability, then I would highly recommend that you do what I did and try both for about a week. If you’re feeling confident, skip straight to Codecademy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recommend taking the “projects” in either suite very seriously. Don’t just do the minimum prompt. Try to add about twice as much as they ask for. Have fun with it and make it personal. I think this is where the real &lt;em&gt;learning&lt;/em&gt; happens, since the lessons themselves are just prompting you to temporarily memorize some tags and syntax. Putting them into use in the projects is the most beneficial part of the whole process!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best of luck learning a fun new skill!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Dave&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://daveas.me/posts/Learn-to-Code-Codeacademy-vs-Treehouse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daveas.me/posts/Learn-to-Code-Codeacademy-vs-Treehouse/</guid>
        
        <category>Coding</category>
        
        <category>Learning</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do we over-glorify engineering?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For most engineers, “engineering” is not quotidian. It usually matters a lot more if you can “talk to people” rather than “engineer things”, as it goes with so many other jobs. I believe there are many jobs out there that require engineering degrees that simply don’t have to. There should be a faster route to access many of these jobs which are in desperate need of more candidates. Why isn’t there a 2-3 year track that attempts to make one literate in all kinds of engineering with more practical knowledge than fundamental knowledge? A person with that sort of background would make an excellent sales person, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://postachio-images.s3-website-us-east-1.amazonaws.com/0565e242ca8c79566fb38e0a28ff6fbc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;EngineerMeme.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean really, if you’re an engineer you have to love that meme. It’s so true! I think we over-glorify engineering. There are people out there who truly engineer amazing things, but those people are not nearly as common as the rest. The ones who are actually quite content not being among the creative minority. Why don’t we glorify engineering literacy, much like we are starting to push (perhaps over-glorify) &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.motherjones.com/media/2014/06/computer-science-programming-code-diversity-sexism-education?utm_source=pocket&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pockethits&quot;&gt;coding literacy&lt;/a&gt;? I mean, why is it that most &lt;em&gt;new engineering graduates&lt;/em&gt; could not fix a carburator or program an arduino? If you’re not a recent grad that might surprise you, but these people are the minority. There has to be a faster, better way to take a person from high school education to engineering literate in less than four years. We desperately need it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://daveas.me/posts/Do-we-over-glorify-engineering/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daveas.me/posts/Do-we-over-glorify-engineering/</guid>
        
        <category>Engineering</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Farewell to thee, Willow List</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I came to a difficult decision. I decided to pull the plug on our startup, Willow List.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://postachio-images.s3-website-us-east-1.amazonaws.com/74eb28143e6bb5b350321213ffddb680.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;starting-up&quot;&gt;Starting Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Willow List started after the summer before my senior year of college, when I read a book called &lt;a href=&quot;http://godownwind.co/go-down-wind&quot;&gt;The One Thing&lt;/a&gt;. This book challenged me to find the one overarching theme in my professional life. I decided mine had to do with something I had never done before, creating companies out of ideas. So I set out to do it before I graduated, knowing I would need a head-start going into the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sorted through my Evernote folder titled “Ideas for Ventures” but I wasn’t compelled by any of the hundreds of ideas within. Instead, inspiration came at the dinner table with my girlfriend (now &lt;a href=&quot;http://godownwind.co/my-engagement-story&quot;&gt;fiancé&lt;/a&gt;) and our two friends, Natalie and Chase. Nat and Chase were talking about registering because they were to be engaged soon. They mentioned they would not add an espresso machine to their list because of cost. A lightbulb went off because I had been reading about Kickstarter earlier in the day. I thought a registry where each item was it’s own Kickstarter campaign was a pretty fresh idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started looking into the industry, signing up for one of every registry I could find eventually losing count around 30. I realized there were a load of pain points in the industry - 90’s scanner guns, duplicate gifts, limited selections, clunky UX and ugly UI. This was it. I could convince a few other people, and together we would create a better registry. How hard could it be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;running-along&quot;&gt;Running Along&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward several months and we now had a CTO, a few senior business partners, and Tennessee’s best wedding resource The Pink Bride as a partner. We had a business model wherein we did two things incredibly well. The first was to “crowd-fund” individual products on a registry, and second was to deliver these products to the end customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through personal experience and discussions with potential investors we came to realize that the crowd-funding feature would quickly become a commodity feature amongst our competitors. But the real problem in the business model came from the inability to deliver products. So we came up with a hypothesis - that we could order these products through affiliate marketing links (links that when clicked throw a few bucks from following purchases back to the one who shared the link). We tested that hypothesis and realized that the model wouldn’t really work for various reasons. So, we decided to “pivot” and go in a new direction. Our next hypothesis was that regional stores had the capacity to ship products and pay a similar kickback to us. We also loved the idea of supporting local business and creating a more unique registry experience. As it turns out, our second hypothesis didn’t work out as we expected either. As it turns out, this stuff is pretty hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;winding-down&quot;&gt;Winding Down&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lacking a way to deliver products to the customer we would only be able to deliver cash, which would likely reduce our gross margins by 4-16%. With a multitude of entrenched competitors with identical features, and new entrants like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stylemepretty.com/2014/01/21/wedding-registry-with-zola&quot;&gt;Zola&lt;/a&gt; we were hard pressed to find a pivot that was worth the years of struggle that follow starting a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked for other pivots — new and exciting areas where we could apply what we had learned. But ultimately David (cofounder and CTO) and I agreed that we didn’t see anything that was well… worth it. We needed to see two things: &lt;strong&gt;huge potential in the problem&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;business value&lt;/em&gt;) and &lt;strong&gt;legitimate passion about the solution&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;personal value&lt;/em&gt;). In the end, we only saw one of those things everywhere we looked, so we decided the only thing to do for ourselves was call the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;looking-forward&quot;&gt;Looking Forward&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been pleasantly surprised by my overall mood since. This happens more often than not - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.statisticbrain.com/startup-failure-by-industry&quot;&gt;startups fail&lt;/a&gt;. But while we failed to create a “successful” startup, we were successful in creating a great team and in learning about what to do next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-there-will-be-a-next-time&quot;&gt;And there will be a next time!&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://daveas.me/posts/Farewell-to-thee-Willow-List/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daveas.me/posts/Farewell-to-thee-Willow-List/</guid>
        
        <category>Willowlist</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Engineers as Entrepreneurs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An education in engineering is a four year test to see if you can &lt;em&gt;solve problems&lt;/em&gt;. If you can, you’re not limited to engineering, are you?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://daveas.me/posts/Engineers-as-Entrepreneurs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daveas.me/posts/Engineers-as-Entrepreneurs/</guid>
        
        <category>Engineering</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building local PR</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Shout out to KNS for posting this little blurb about our Vol-Court win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://postachio-files.s3-website-us-east-1.amazonaws.com/3a7ee5c2b937a71a42fb29054359cd7e.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://daveas.me/posts/Building-local-PR/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daveas.me/posts/Building-local-PR/</guid>
        
        <category>Willowlist</category>
        
        
        <category>archive</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Screenfloat - keep an image in the foreground</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Applications for Mac may be mostly dead as mobile becomes dominant. But as Miracle Max proved once before, that which is mostly dead can still come back in the form of a giant fiery pirate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://postachio-images.s3-website-us-east-1.amazonaws.com/689ba222420a8fecfc95eec7daf25d3a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;miracle-max.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below you can see I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.screenfloatapp.com/&quot;&gt;Screenfloat&lt;/a&gt; (which lives in the menu bar) to snap a photo of a table in excel. That photo is no hovering over all other applications, including the word document I’m currently writing in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://postachio-images.s3-website-us-east-1.amazonaws.com/942f3d1dfda7ce8bba7dde518bb8465c.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thanks-screenfloat&quot;&gt;Thanks Screenfloat&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://daveas.me/posts/Screenfloat-keep-an-image-in-the-foreground/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daveas.me/posts/Screenfloat-keep-an-image-in-the-foreground/</guid>
        
        <category>How I Work</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
